algebra_1_part_1 = {
    "Algebra foundations": [
        {
            "Introduction to variables": {
            "Definition": "Variables in math are symbols, often letters, that represent different values in various situations. They help us understand and solve problems with changing values. For example, when calculating total earnings at a job with an hourly wage plus tips, a variable can represent the fluctuating tips, making it easier to determine total income.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Does the equation x^2 + x + 1 have 2 variables?",
                        "Answer": "No, the equation has 1 variable which is x.",
                        "Type": "Boolean",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Substitution and evaluating expressions": {
            "Definition": "Evaluating expressions with multiple variables involves substituting given values for each variable and simplifying the expression. By replacing variables with their corresponding values, we can easily compute the result of expressions, even for more complex examples with multiple terms and operations.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Consider the expression \(3x^2 - 5y + 2xy + 4\) with \(x = -2\) and \(y = 3\). Evaluate the expression when the given values for \(x\) and \(y\) are substituted.",
                        "Answer": "Substituting x = -2 and y = 3 to the equation, we obtain 3 * (-2)^2 - 5*5 + 2 * (-2) * 3 + 4 = -21. The answer is -21.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Solving equations and inequalities": [
        {
            "Linear equations with variables on both sides": {
                "Definition": "Worked example: Learn to solve the equation 2x + 3 = 5x - 2. ",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Solve the equation 2x + 3 = 5x - 2.",
                        "Answer": "The expression 2x + 3 = 5x - 2 is equivalent to 5 = 3x. So x = 5/3.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Linear equations with parentheses": {
                "Definition": "Sal solves the equation -9 - (9x - 6) = 3(4x + 6) using the distributive property.",
                "QA Queue": [
                        {
                            "Question": "Solves the equation -9 - (9x - 6) = 3(4x + 6).",
                            "Answer": "The expression -9 - (9x - 6) = 3(4x + 6) is equivalent to -3 - 9x = 12x + 18. The expression -3 - 9x = 12x + 18 is equivalent to -21x = 21. Solving this equation, we obtain x = -1. ",
                            "Type": "Narrative",
                            "Difficulty": 3
                        }
                    ],
                "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Analyzing the number of solutions to linear equations": {
                "Definition": "Sal attempts to solve 8(3x + 10) = 28x - 14 - 4x only to find that the equation has no solution.",
                "QA Queue": [
                        {
                            "Question": "Solves the equation 8(3x + 10) = 28x - 14 - 4x).",
                            "Answer": "Suppose that the equation has a solution, the expression 8(3x + 10) = 28x - 14 - 4x) is quivalent to 24x + 80 = 24x - 14, which is equivalent to 80 = -14, which is logically wrong. So the equation has no solution.",
                            "Type": "Narrative",
                            "Difficulty": 3
                        }
                    ],
                "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Linear equations with unknown coefficients": {
                "Definition": "Sal solves the equations ax+3x=bx+5 and a(5-x)=bx-8 for x. Note that these equations include other unknowns (a and b) but we solve them for x.",
                "QA Queue": [
                        {
                            "Question": "Solves the equations ax+3x=bx+5 and a(5-x)=bx-8 for x.",
                            "Answer": "Narrative",
                            "Type": "",
                            "Difficulty": 3
                        }
                    ],
                "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Multi-step inequalities": {
                "Definition": "Sal solves the inequality -3p-7<p+9, draws the solution on a number line and checks a few values to verify the solution.",
                "QA Queue": [
                        {
                            "Question": "Solves the inequality -3p-7<p+9?",
                            "Answer": "The expression -3p-7<p+9 is equivalent to -16 < 4p, which is equivalent to -4 < p.",
                            "Type": "Narrative",
                            "Difficulty": 3
                        }
                    ],
                "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Compound inequalities": {
                "Definition": "A compound inequality is an inequality that combines two simple inequalities.",
                "QA Queue": [
                        {
                            "Question": "Find all intergers x such as 7 \leq 2x + 1 \leq 15.",
                            "Answer":"The expression 7 \leq 2x + 1 is equivalent to 3 \leq x, and 2x + 1 \leq 15 is equivalent to x \leq 7. Thus, the answer is 3 \leq x \leq 7.",
                            "Type": "Narrative",
                            "Difficulty": 3
                        }
                    ],
                "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
    ],
    "Working with units": [
        {
            "Rate conversion": {
                "Definition": "Sal shows how we can treat units of measurement algebraically, and use these tools in order to convert between different units of the same quantity.",
                "QA Queue": [
                        {
                            "Question": "Convert 10cm to meter?",
                            "Answer": "10cm = 0.1m",
                            "Type": "Narrative",
                            "Difficulty": 2
                        }
                    ],
                "Rate": 1,
                }
        },
        {
            "Word problems with multiple units": {
                "Definition": "In word problems that involve multiple quantities, we can use the units of the quantities to guide our solution.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": " If 1 pound = 16 ounces, how many pounds are in 435 ounces?",
                        "Answer": "435 ounces is 435/16 pounds.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 2
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Linear equations and graphs": [
        {
            "Two-variable linear equations intro": {
                "Definition": "The solution of an equation with one variable is a number. How does the solution of a 2-variable equation look like? Well, it is an ordered pair",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Given the equation -3x + 7y = 5x + 2y. If x = -5, what is the value of y?",
                        "Answer": "The equation -3x + 7y = 5x + 2y is equivalent to 8x = 5y. Substitute x = -5 we obtain y = -8.",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Horizontal and vertical lines": {
                "Definition": "Horizontal lines are lines that have a slope of 0, meaning they don't go up or down, while vertical lines have an undefined slope, meaning they don't go left or right.",
                "QA Queue": [
                        {
                            "Question": "What is the line y = 3?",
                            "Answer": "The line y = 3 is a horizontal line which is parallel to x-axis, and passes through the point y = 3.",
                            "Type": "",
                            "Difficulty": 3
                        }
                    ],
                "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "x-intercepts and y-intercepts": {
                "Definition": "The x-intercept is where a line crosses the x-axis, and the y-intercept is the point where the line crosses the y-axis. Thinking about intercepts helps us graph linear equations.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Given the line y = 2x + 2. What are the x-intercepts and y-intercepts?",
                        "Answer": "When y = 0, x = -1 so the x-intercept is (-1, 0). When x = 0, y = 2 so the y-intercept is (0, 2).",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
    ],
    "Forms of linear equations": [
        {
            "Slope-intercept form": {
                "Definition": "The slope intercept form is given as, y = mx + b, where 'm' is the slope of the straight line and 'b' is the y-intercept.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Conrad read a 180-page book cover to cover in a single session, at a constant rate. It took him 6 hours. What is his rate?",
                        "Answer": "His rate is 180/6=30 pages per hour.",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Point-slope form": {
                "Definition": "Point-slope form is another way to write a linear equation. The form is y - y1 = m(x - x1)",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Complete the point-slope equation of the line through (-1, -10) and (5,2).",
                        "Answer": "Let y = ax + b, we have -10 = -a + b and 2 = 5a + b. Solve the system of equations, we obtain a = 2 and b = -8. Thus y - 2 = 2 (x - 5).",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Standard form": {
                "Definition": "Standard form is yet another way to write a linear equation. The form is Ax + By = C where A, B, C are constant.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "What is y + 4 = -6(x + 6) written in the standard form?",
                        "Answer": "y + 4 = -6(x + 6) written in the standard form is 6x + y = -40.",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ]
}

algebra_1_part_2 = {
    "Systems of equations": [
        {
            "Solving systems of equations with elimination": {
                "Definition": "Sal solves the following system of equations by eliminating x: x-4y=-18 and -x+3y=11.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Solve the system of equations: x-4y=-18 and -x+3y=11?",
                        "Answer": "From the first equation x-4y=-18, we derive that x = -18 + 4y. Substitute this to the second equation -x+3y=11, we have -(-18 + 4y) + 3y = 11. Solve this equation, we have y = 7. Therefore, we can find x = 10.",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "Systems of equations number of solutions": {
                "Definition": "A system of linear equations usually has a single solution, but sometimes it can have no solution (parallel lines) or infinite solutions (same line). This article reviews all three cases.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "How many solutions does the system have? x + 2y = 2 and 2x + 4y = -8",
                        "Answer": "Let's rewrite the equations in slope-intercept form (y = mx + b), where m is the slope and b is the y-intercept: \n\n Equation 1: x + 2y = 2\n2y = -x + 2\ny = -0.5x + 1\n\nEquation 2: 2x + 4y = -8\n4y = -2x - 8\ny = -0.5x - 2\nBoth equations have the same slope (-0.5). When two lines have the same slope but different y-intercepts, they are parallel and will never intersect. In this case, the lines represented by the equations are parallel.\nTherefore, the system of equations has no solution.",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
    "Inequalities": [
        {
            "Checking solutions of two variable inequalities": {
                "Definition": "Sal checks if the ordered pairs (3,5) and (1,-7) are solutions of the inequality 5x-3y≥25.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Is (0,-1) a solution of -10x + 4y >= -4?",
                        "Answer": "To determine whether the point (0, -1) is a solution of the inequality -10x + 4y >= -4, we can substitute the values of x and y into the inequality and check if the inequality holds true.\n\nLet's substitute x = 0 and y = -1 into the inequality:\n\n-10(0) + 4(-1) >= -4\n0 - 4 >= -4\n-4 >= -4\n\nThe inequality -4 >= -4 is true. Therefore, the point (0, -1) is a solution of the inequality -10x + 4y >= -4.",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1,
            },
        }
    ],
    "Functions": [
        {
            "Expressive functions": {
                "Definition": "A function is a mathematical rule that matches inputs to outputs. We can think of it like a machine: put a number in, the machine does some calculations, and out pops a corresponding number.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "g(r) = 25-3r. Then g(4) is equal to what?",
                        "Answer": "To find g(4), we need to substitute the value of r = 4 into the expression for g(r) = 25 - 3r.\n\ng(4) = 25 - 3(4)\n= 25 - 12\n= 13\n\nTherefore, g(4) is equal to 13.",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        },
        {
            "Domain and range of a function": {
                "Definition": "The domain is the set of all possible inputs that the function can take, while the range is the set of all outputs the function can produce.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Consider the function f(x) = \sqrt(4 - x^2). Determine the domain and the range of the function. ",
                        "Answer": '''Let's solve this step by step:

Domain:
The domain of a function is the set of all possible values of x for which the function is defined. In this case, since we have a square root function, the radicand (the expression inside the square root) must be non-negative.
4 - x^2 ≥ 0
x^2 ≤ 4
-2 ≤ x ≤ 2

Therefore, the domain of the function f(x) is -2 ≤ x ≤ 2.

Range:
The range of a function is the set of all possible values that the function can take on. For this particular function, we have a square root function, which means the range will be limited to non-negative values.
Since the function involves a square root, we know that the output will always be greater than or equal to 0. Thus, the range of the function f(x) is f(x) ≥ 0, or [0, +∞).

In summary:
Domain: -2 ≤ x ≤ 2
Range: [0, +∞)
                        ''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        },
        {
            "Function is increasing or decreasing": {
                "Definition": "A function is increasing over an interval if the outputs get larger as the inputs increase. A function is decreasing if the outputs get smaller as the inputs increase.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Consider the function f(x) = 2x + 3. Determine whether the function is increasing, decreasing, or neither.",
                        "Answer": "In the given function f(x) = 2x + 3, we can observe that the coefficient of x is positive (2 > 0). If u >= v, then f(u) >= f(v). Therefore, the function f(x) = 2x + 3 is an increasing function.",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        },
        {
            "Inverse functions": {
                "Definition": "Inverse functions are functions that 'undo' each other. If we plug the output of one function into the inverse function, we get back the original input.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Sal finds the inverses of f(x)=-x+4.",
                        "Answer": '''To find the inverse of the function f(x) = -x + 4, we can follow these steps:

Step 1: Replace f(x) with y: y = -x + 4.

Step 2: Swap x and y: x = -y + 4.

Step 3: Solve the equation for y. To do this, isolate y on one side of the equation:

x = -y + 4
x - 4 = -y
-1(x - 4) = y

x + 4 = y
Step 4: Replace y with the inverse notation f^(-1)(x):

f^(-1)(x) = -x + 4.

Therefore, the inverse of the function f(x) = -x + 4 is f^(-1)(x) = -x + 4.''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        }
    ],
    "Sequences": [
        {
            "Arithmetic sequence and a geometric sequence": {
                "Definition": "In an arithmetic sequence, we add the same number to each term in order to get the next term in the sequence. In a geometric sequence, we multiply each term by the same number in order to get the next term.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "What is the next term of the arithmetic sequence? -3, 0, 3, 6, 9",
                        "Answer": '''The given sequence is an arithmetic sequence with a common difference of 3. To find the next term, we can add the common difference to the last term of the sequence.

The last term of the sequence is 9, and the common difference is 3. Adding 3 to 9, we get:

9 + 3 = 12

Therefore, the next term of the arithmetic sequence -3, 0, 3, 6, 9 is 12.''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        },
        {
            "Recursive formula and an explicit formula for a sequence": {
                "Definition": "An explicit formula allows us to calculate the value of any term in the sequence by plugging in the term number, while a recursive formula defines each term in the sequence in relation to the terms that came before it.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": '''To find the 4th item of the sequence defined by the recursive formula b(n) = b(n-1)*(-3), where b(1) = 15, we can calculate the values step by step.

b(1) = 15 (given)

b(2) = b(1)(-3) = 15(-3) = -45

b(3) = b(2)(-3) = -45(-3) = 135

b(4) = b(3)(-3) = 135(-3) = -405

Therefore, the 4th item of the sequence is -405.''',
                        "Answer": "",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        },
        {
            "Absolute value": {
                "Definition": "Absolute value is a function that outputs the distance of any input from 0 on the number line.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "We're asked to graph: f(x) = -2|x| + 4",
                        "Answer": "The graph of the function f(x) = -2|x| + 4 is a V-shaped curve, opening downwards, with the vertex point at (0, 4).",
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        },
        {
            "Piecewise functions": {
                "Definition": "Piecewise functions are functions that are defined in separate 'pieces' for different intervals of the input.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": '''Consider the function f(x) defined as:

f(x) =
2x + 3 if x < 1
x^2 if x >= 1

Evaluate f(0).
Evaluate f(1).
Evaluate f(2).''',
                        "Answer": '''Let's solve this step by step:

To evaluate f(0), we substitute x = 0 into the piecewise function:
Since 0 < 1, we use the first part of the function:
f(0) = 2(0) + 3 = 0 + 3 = 3.

To evaluate f(1), we substitute x = 1 into the piecewise function:
Since 1 >= 1, we use the second part of the function:
f(1) = (1)^2 = 1.

To evaluate f(2), we substitute x = 2 into the piecewise function:
Since 2 >= 1, we use the second part of the function:
f(2) = (2)^2 = 4.

Therefore:

f(0) = 3.
f(1) = 1.
f(2) = 4.''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        }
    ],
    "Exponents and radicals": [
        {
            "Exponent properties": {
                "Definition": "Product rule, Power rule, Quotient rule, Zero exponent rule",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": '''Rewrite the expression in the form 4^n: (4^6)*(4^)-8))''',
                        "Answer": '''To rewrite the expression (4^6)*(4^-8) in the form 4^n, we can use the properties of exponents.

Recall that when multiplying numbers with the same base, we can add their exponents:

(4^6)*(4^-8) = 4^(6 + -8) = 4^(-2)''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        },
        {
            "Radicals": {
                "Definition": "A radical is a symbol that we use to write square roots, cube roots, and other roots. ",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Find the 4th root of 81",
                        "Answer": '''The 4th root of 81 can be found by raising 81 to the power of 1/4.

81^(1/4) = 3

Therefore, the 4th root of 81 is 3.''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        }
    ]
}

algebra_1_part_3 = {
    "Exponential growth and decay": [
        {
            "Exponential and linear growth": {
                "Definition": "In linear growth, we add or subtract the same amount each time period, while in exponential growth, we multiply by the same factor each time period. For example, linear growth might involve adding 5 each day, while exponential growth might involve multiplying by 2 each day.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": '''Every year  39 million cars cross the Golden Gate Bridge in San Francisco.
Which kind of function best models the relationship between time and the cumulative number of cars that have crossed the Golden Gate Bridge?''',
                        "Answer": '''The relationship between time and the cumulative number of cars that have crossed the Golden Gate Bridge can be modeled by an exponential function.

An exponential function is characterized by a constant base raised to a variable exponent. In this case, as time progresses, the number of cars crossing the bridge is expected to grow exponentially.''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        },
        {
            "Exponential growth and exponential decay": {
                "Definition": "While both involve exponential functions, exponential growth refers to when the quantity is increasing over time, while exponential decay refers to when the quantity is decreasing over time.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Moore's law says that the number of transistors in a dense integrated circuit increases by 41% percent every year. In 1974, a dense integrated circuit was produced with  5000 transistors. Which expression gives the number of transistors in a dense integrated circuit in 1979?",
                        "Answer": '''To determine the number of transistors in a dense integrated circuit in 1979, given that Moore's law states a 41% increase in transistors every year, we can use the following expression:

N = 5000 * (1 + 0.41)^t

In this expression, N represents the number of transistors, 5000 is the initial number of transistors in 1974, 0.41 is the 41% increase expressed as a decimal, and t represents the number of years since the initial year.

To find the number of transistors in 1979, we need to calculate the value of t. Since 1979 is 5 years after 1974, we substitute t = 5 into the expression:

N = 5000 * (1 + 0.41)^5

Calculating this expression:

N = 5000 * (1.41)^5
N = 5000 * 3.9235
N ≈ 19617

Therefore, the number of transistors in a dense integrated circuit in 1979, following Moore's law, is approximately 19,617.''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        }
    ],
    "Quadratics, Multiplying, Factoring, Quadratics equations": [
        {
            "Monomial": {
                "Definition": "A monomial is an algebraic expression that has just one term.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Simplify the monomial expression 3x^2 * 4x^3.",
                        "Answer": '''To simplify this expression, we can multiply the coefficients (numbers) and add the exponents of the same variable (in this case, x).

3x^2 * 4x^3 = 3 * 4 * x^2 * x^3

Multiplying the coefficients:
3 * 4 = 12

Combining the x terms:
x^2 * x^3 = x^(2+3) = x^5

Putting it all together:
3x^2 * 4x^3 = 12x^5

Therefore, the simplified form of the monomial expression 3x^2 * 4x^3 is 12x^5.''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            },
            "Binomial": {
                "Definition": "A binomial is an algebraic expression that has two terms.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": '''Expand.
Your answer should be a polynomial in standard form. (9b-1)(9b+1)''',
                        "Answer": '''To expand the expression (9b - 1)(9b + 1), we can use the FOIL method, which stands for First, Outer, Inner, Last. It allows us to multiply each term in the first binomial by each term in the second binomial.

Applying the FOIL method:

(9b - 1)(9b + 1) = (9b * 9b) + (9b * 1) + (-1 * 9b) + (-1 * 1)

Simplifying further:

= 81b^2 + 9b - 9b - 1

Combining like terms:

= 81b^2 - 1

Therefore, the expanded form of (9b - 1)(9b + 1) is 81b^2 - 1, which is a polynomial in standard form.''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            },
            "Polynomial": {
                "Definition": "A polynomial is an algebraic expression made up of one or more terms. Monomials and binomials are both types of polynomials.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "What is the degree of the polynomial expression 3x^4 + 2x^3 - 5x^2 + 7x - 1?",
                        "Answer": '''To determine the degree of a polynomial, we look at the term with the highest exponent. In the given polynomial expression:

3x^4 + 2x^3 - 5x^2 + 7x - 1

The term with the highest exponent is 3x^4. Therefore, the degree of the polynomial expression is 4.

So, the degree of the polynomial expression 3x^4 + 2x^3 - 5x^2 + 7x - 1 is 4.''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            },
            "Factor an expression": {
                "Definition": "Factoring an expression means breaking it down into simpler parts that we can multiply together to get the original expression.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Factor as the product of two binomials x^2 + x - 12.",
                        "Answer": '''To factor the quadratic expression x^2 + x - 12, we are looking for two binomials in the form (x + a)(x + b) that can be multiplied together to give the original expression.

To find the values of a and b, we need to identify two numbers that multiply to give -12 and add up to +1 (which is the coefficient of the x term).

By considering the factors of -12, we see that -3 and +4 satisfy these conditions. Therefore, we can factor the expression as:

x^2 + x - 12 = (x - 3)(x + 4).

So, the expression x^2 + x - 12 factors as the product of two binomials: (x - 3)(x + 4).''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            },
            "Vertex form":{
                "Definition": "Vertex form is another way of writing a quadratic equation. It looks like this: f(x)=a(x−h)^2 + k",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": '''A hovercraft takes off from a platform.
Its height (in meters), x seconds after takeoff, is modeled by: h(x)=−3(x−3)^2 +108.
What is the height of the hovercraft at the time of takeoff?''',
                        "Answer": '''To find the height of the hovercraft at the time of takeoff, we need to evaluate the function h(x) when x is equal to 0.

Given the function h(x) = -3(x-3)^2 + 108, we substitute x = 0:

h(0) = -3(0-3)^2 + 108

Simplifying further:

h(0) = -3(-3)^2 + 108
     = -3(9) + 108
     = -27 + 108
     = 81

Therefore, the height of the hovercraft at the time of takeoff is 81 meters.''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            },
            "Quadratic": {
                "Definition": "A quadratic is a type of function that can be written in the form f(x) = ax^2 + bx + c with a, b, c are constants.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Solve 10x^2 - 9x - 6.",
                        "Answer": '''To solve the quadratic equation 10x^2 - 9x - 6, we can use the quadratic formula:

x = (-b ± √(b^2 - 4ac)) / (2a)

For the given equation, a = 10, b = -9, and c = -6. Substituting these values into the quadratic formula:

x = (-(-9) ± √((-9)^2 - 4 * 10 * -6)) / (2 * 10)
  = (9 ± √(81 + 240)) / 20
  = (9 ± √321) / 20

Therefore, the solutions to the quadratic equation 10x^2 - 9x - 6 are:

x = (9 + √321) / 20
x = (9 - √321) / 20''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            },
            "Parabola": {
                "Definition": "A parabola is the shape of the graph of a quadratic function. It looks like a symmetrical 'U' shape, and can open either up or down depending on the function.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": '''The parabola y=x^22 is shifted down by 6 units and to the right by 5 units. What is the equation of the new parabola?''',
                        "Answer": '''To shift the parabola y = x^2 down by 6 units, we subtract 6 from the original equation:

y = x^2 - 6

To shift the resulting parabola to the right by 5 units, we replace x with (x - 5) in the equation:

y = (x - 5)^2 - 6

Expanding the square:

y = (x - 5)(x - 5) - 6
  = x^2 - 10x + 25 - 6
  = x^2 - 10x + 19

Therefore, the equation of the new parabola, obtained by shifting the original parabola y = x^2 down by 6 units and to the right by 5 units, is y = x^2 - 10x + 19.''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        }
    ],
    "Irrational numbers": [
        {
            "Irrational numbers": {
                "Definition": "An irrational number is a real number that cannot be written as a ratio of two integers. In other words, it can't be written as a fraction where the numerator and denominator are both integers. Irrational numbers often show up as non-terminating, non-repeating decimals.",
                "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Is the following number rational or irrational? \sqrt(200)",
                        "Answer": '''To determine if the number √200 is rational or irrational, we need to check if it can be expressed as a fraction of two integers.

√200 can be simplified as follows:
√200 = √(100 * 2) = √100 * √2 = 10√2

Since 10√2 is not a fraction of two integers, we can conclude that √200 is an irrational number.''',
                        "Type": "",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
                "Rate": 1
            }
        },
    ]
}